Guide to the Maurepas collection, 1694-1749
Maurepas collection, 1694-1749
- Series II. Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence
  - 1745
    - Richelieu, Louis-François Armand du Plessis, duc de, 1696-1788 LS to Maurpas June 2, 1745 [n.p.], 2 ll. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Richelieu, Louis-François Armand du Plessis, duc de, 1696-1788 LS to Maurepas June 8, 1745 [?], 2 ll. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Le Clerc ALS to Maurepas July 23, 1745. Le Havre, 1 l. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Rebel, François, 1701-1775 LS to Salley August 8, 1745. Paris, 4 ll. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Rebel, François, 1701-1775 LS to Salley August 9, 1745. Paris, 4 ll. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - James III (Stuart), "The Old Pretender," 1688-1766 LS to Maurepas August 11, 1745. Rome, 2 ll. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Maurepas, Jean-Frédéric Phélypeaux, comte de, 1701-1781 L [Draft] to François Rebel August 11, 1745. Versailles, 1 l. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Orleans, Jean-Philippe, Chavalier du, 1702-1748 ALS to Maurepas August 14, 1745. St. Cloud, 1 l. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Le Clerc, ALS to Maurepas September 6, 1745. Paris, 1 l. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - de la Mothe, Jacques Bigot LS to Maurepas September 8, 1745. Brest, 4 ll. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Cuppi, Anne-Marie, called "Camargo," 1710-1770 ALS to Maurepas September 26, 1745. Paris, 3 ll. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - De Lage de Cueilly, ALS to Maurepas September 28, 1745 [Toulon], 4 ll. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - de la Mothe, Jacques Bigot LS to Maurepas October 1, 1745. Brest, 3 ll. (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Berger, ALS to Mlle. Rotisset de Romainville October 2, [1745] [Paris], 1 l. (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Berger, ALS to Mlle. Rotisset de Romainville October 7, 1745 [Paris], 1 l. (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Romainville, Mlle. Rotisset de L [copy] to Maurepas October 8, 1745 [n.p.], 1 l. (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - De Lage de Cueilly, ALS to Maurepas October 12, 1745. Fontainbleau, 1 l. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - O'Bryen, ALS to Maurepas October 15, 1745. Paris, 3 ll. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - O'Heguarty, Pierre André, 1700-1763 ALS to Maurepas October 15, 1745. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Berger, ALS to Maurepas October 18, 1745. Paris, 4 ll. (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Fournier, ALS to Maurepas October 19, 1745. Paris, 4 ll. (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Polignac, de Maily, vicomtesse de ALS to Maurepas October 23, 1745., 2 ll. (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - 1745 - 1746
    - Polignac, de Mailly, vicomtesse de ALS to Maurepas October 25, 1745., 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Saint-Simon, Louis de Rouvra, duc de, 1675-1755 ALS to Maurepas October 26, 1745 [?], 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Romainville, Rotisset de, LS to Maurepas October 29, 1745. Paris, 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Mailly-Nesle, Armande de la Porte Mazarin, marquise de, AL to Salley November 23, 1745., 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - O'Bryen, ALS to Maurepas November 28, 1745. Bagneaux, 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Richelieu, Louis-François-Armand, duc de, 1696-1788 ALS to Maurepas [December 1745] Dunkerque., 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Fitzjames, Charles, duc de, 1712-1787 LS to Maurepas December 8, 1745. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Langerie, ALS to Maurepas December 24, 1745. Marseilles, 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount, Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas December 25, 1745. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Walsh, Anthony Vincent, d. 1763 ALS to Maurepas December 25, 1745. Paris, 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount, Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas December 26, 1745. Paris, 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Charron, ALS to Maurepas December 29, 1745. Dunkerque, 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount, Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas December 29, 1745. Boulogne, 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Maurepas, Jean-Frédéric Phélypeaux, comte de, 1701-1781 AL [Draft] to Richelieu December [?] 31, 1745., 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Orleans, Jean-Philippe, Chevalier du 1702-1748 ALS [Draft] to Maurepas [1746] [n.p.], 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Orleans, Jean-Philippe, Chevalier du 1702-1748 L [copy] to Louis XV [1746] [n.p.], 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Walsh, Anthony Vincent, d. 1763 D [Memoire du Roy pour servir d'instruction au S. Wailsh...] [ca. 1746] [n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Maurepas, Jean-Frédéric Phélpeaux, comte de, 1701-1781 L to Maupeou [176-1747] [n.p.], 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, ALS to Maurepas 1746-1747. Luneville, 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, ALS to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, ALS to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, ALS to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, ALS [init.] to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, ALS to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas [1746-1747] [n.p.], 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas "Lundi soir..." [1746-1747], 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas "Jeudi" [1746-1747] [n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas "Jeudi au soir" [1746-1747] [n.p.], 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Richelieu, Louis-François-Armand, duc de, 1696-1788 ALS to Maurepas January 2, 1746. Boulogne, 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Saint-Simon, Louis de Rouvray, duc de, 1675-1755 ALS to Maurepas January 2, 1746 [?], 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Kearney, ALS to Charles O'Brien, Viscount Clare Earl of Thomond January 4, 1746. Rochefort, 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, ALS to Louis XV January 4, 1746. Calais, 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 4, 1746. Boulogne, 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 5, 1746. Calais, 1 l. (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 6, 1746. Calais, 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 9, 1746. Calais, 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Maulevrier, Christophe Andrault de Langeron, comte de, ALS to Maurepas January 10, 1746. Marseilles, 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 10, 1746. Calais, 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - L'Etanduère, Henri-François des Herbiers de, ALS to Maurepas January 11, 1746. Rochefort, 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Pilles, Chevalier de, ALS to Maurepas January 12, 1746. Marseilles, 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 14, 1746. Calais, 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Fournier, ALS to Maurepas January 15, 1746. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 16, 1746. Calais, 3 ll. (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 21, 1746. Calais, 4 ll. (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - 1746
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 26, 1746. Calais, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - York, Henry Benedict Stuart, Duke of, 1725-1807 ALS to Maurepas January 27, 1746. Boulogne sur Mer, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 28, 1746. Boulogne, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas January 28, 1746. Calais, 4 ll. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas February 1, 1746. Calais, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas February 5, 1746. Dunkerque, 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Saint-Simon, Louis de Rouvray, duc de, 1675-1755 ALS to Maurepas February 8, 1746. [?], 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas February 8, 1746. Dunkerque, 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - York, Henry Benedict Stuart, Duke of, 1725-1807 ALS to Maurepas February 11, 1746. Boulogne sur Mer., 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas February 13, 1746. Dunkerque, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas February 15, 1746. Dunkerque, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Mailly-Nesle, Armande de la Porte Mazarin, marquise de AL to Maurepas February 16, 1746., 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas February 18, 1746. Dunkerque, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Mailly-Nesle, Armande de la Porte Mazarin, marquise de AL to Maurepas February 21, 1746., 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas February 21, 1746. Dunkerque, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas February 28, 1746. Dunkerque, 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas March 1, 1746. Dunkerque, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Keith, George Keith, 1693-1778 ALS to Maurepas March 2, 1746. Paris, 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas March 4, 1746. Dunkerque, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Fitzjames, Charles, comte de, L [copy] to Charles O'Brien, Viscount Clare, Earl of Thomond March 5, 1746., 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, Earl of AL to Maurepas March 6, 1746. Dunkerque, 4 ll. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, Earl of AL to Maurepas March 8, 1746. Dunkerque, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas March 11, 1746. Dunkerque, 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas March 14, 1746. Dunkerque, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas March 15, 1746. Dunkerque, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Paris de Monmartal, Jean ALS to Maurepas March 16, 1746. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas March 16, 1746. Dunkerque, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Vierry [?] ALS to Maurepas March 18, 1746., 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas March 19, 1746. Dunkerque, 4 ll. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Paris de Monmartel, Jean ALS to Maurepas March 21, 1746. Paris, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas March 23, 1746. Dunkerque, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, Viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas March 26, 1746. Dunkerque, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Saint-Simon, Louis de Rouvray, duc de, 1675-1746 ALS to Maurepas March 29, 1746. [?], 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas March 29, 1746. Dunkerque, 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas April 5, 1746. Dunkerque, 4 ll. (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas April 7, 1746. Dunkerque, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Louis XV, King of France, 1710-1774 ALS to La Rochefoucauld April 8, 1746. Versailles, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas April 8, 1746. Dunkerque, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - O'Bryen, LS to Maurepas April 13, 1746. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas April 15, 1746. Dunkerque, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Enville, Nicolas de la Rochefoucauld, duc d', 17___-1746 ALS to Louis XV April 16, 1746. Brest, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas April 20, 1746. Dunkerque, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - O'Bryen, ALS to Maurepas May 23, 1746. Paris, 4 ll. (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Mézières, Elénore-Marie-Thèrèse Oglethorpe, marquise de, ALS to Maurepas June 3, 1746 [n.p.], 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Romieu ALS to Maurepas July 1, 1746. Paris, 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Louis XV, King of France, 1710-1774 AL to La Rochefoucauld [September 1746] [n.p.], 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Louis XV, King of France, 1710-1774 ALS to La Rochefoucauld [September 1746] [n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Estourmel, Constantin Louis, commandeur d' LS to Maurepas October 1, 1746. "Trident", 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Montlouet, ALS to Maurepas October 1, 1746 [n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas November 1, 1746. Bruyevre, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Villarzel, M. de ALS to Maurepas November 15, 1746., 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Chavigny, Théodore de ALS to Maurepas November 22, 1746., 3 ll. (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Laffilard, ALS to Maurepas December 1, 1746. Paris, 4 ll. (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Talmond, Anne-Charles Frédéric de la Tremoille, prince de, ALS to Maurepas December 3, 1746. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas December 9, 1746. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Talmond, Anne-Charles Frédéric de la Tremoille, prince de, ALS to Maurepas December 9, 1746. Paris, 4 ll. (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas December 10, 1746. Paris, 1 l. (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - 1746 - 1747
    - Orleans, Jean-Philippe, Chevalier du, 1702-1748 ALS to Maurepas Dcember 12, 1746. Marseilles, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Chavigny, Théodore de ALS to Maurepas December 13, 1746., 7 ll. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1608-1775 ALS to Maurepas December 14, 1746. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Duval, ALS to Maurepas December 19, 1746. "Northumberland", 4 ll. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1755 ALS to Maurepas December 19, 1746. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Desnos, ALS to Maurepas December 21, 1746. Brest, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas December 1, 1746. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas December 29, 1746. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - De la Croix, ALS to Maurepas [1747] [Louvain], 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - [Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775] NOTE [Concerns Talmond separation agreement...] [1747] [Paris], 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Talmond, Anne-Charles Frédéric de la Tremoille, prince de, LS to Stanislas Lyszcynski, King of Poland [1747?] [n.p.], 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688--1775 ALS to Maurepas January 1, 1747. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Stuart, Charles Edward, "The Young Pretender," 1720-1788 ALS to Maurepas January 1, 1748. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Laffilard, LS to Maurepas January 10, 1747. Paris, 6 ll. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - D'Orves, Martini LS to Maurepas January 11, 1747. Toulon, 6 ll. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas January 13, 1747. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Orleans, Jean-Philippe, Chevalier du 1702-1748 ALS [init.] to Maurepas January 13, 1747. Marseilles, 4 ll. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas January 15, 1747. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Chavigny, Théodore de ALS to Maurepas January 17, 1747., 6 ll. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas January 24, 1747. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas January 25, 1747. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas January 26, 1747. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas January 27, 1747. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - de la Mothe, Jacques Bigot LS to Maurepas January 27, 1747. Brest, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - D'Orves, Martini LS to Maurepas February 4, 1747. Toulon, 6 ll. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas February 5, 1747. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - de la Mothe, Jacques Bigot LS to Maurepas February 10, 1747. Brest, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Vilarzel, M. de ALS to Maurepas February 17, 1747., 3 ll. (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - D'Orves, Martini LS to Maurepas February 23, 1747. Toulon, 3 ll. (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Maupeou, René-Charles de, 1688-1775 ALS to Maurepas March 10, 1747. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Maurepas, Jean-Frédéric Phélypeaux, 1701-1781 L to Stanislas Leszcynski, King of Poland March 12, 1747 [n.p.], 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Stuart, Charles Edward, "The Young Pretender," 1720-1788 ALS to Maurepas March 28, 1747. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonwska AL to Maurepas April 13, [1747] Luneville, 4 ll. (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonowska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas April 17, [1747] Luneville, 3 ll. (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas April 18, 1748. Bilsen, 4 ll. (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, L to Maurepas April 21, 1748. Bilsen, 3 ll. (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Talmond, Marie-Louise Jablonwska, princesse de, AL to Maurepas May 20, [1747] Luneville, 4 l. (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas May 21, [1748] Blasvelt, 4 ll. (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas May 23, 1747. Malines, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas May 24, [1748] Blasvelt, 3 ll. (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas May 29, 1747. Malines, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas June 7, [1748] Blasvelt, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Boyer d'Eguilles, Alexandre Jean-Baptiste, marquis de, ALS to Maurepas June 27, 1747. Paris, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Belle-Isle, Charles-Louis-August Fouquet, duc de, 1684-1761 L [copy] to Marquis de la Mina July 9, 1747. Menton, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Biron, Charles-Armand, duc de AL to Maurepas August 26, 1748., 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas October 3, 1747. Alost, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas October 4, 1747. Alost, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas October 9, 1747. Alost, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas October 10, [1747] Louvain, 2 ll. (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas October 21, 1747. Louvain, 3 ll. (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL [copy] to Maurepas October 22, 1747. Louvain, 4 ll. (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Thomond, Charles II O'Brien, viscount Clare, earl of, AL to Maurepas October 26, 1747. Liancour, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Châtelet, François Bernadin, marquis de ALS to Maurepas October 28, 1747. Vincennes, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Pallavicini, Gianluca LS to Maurepas October 29, 1747. Paris, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Stuart, Charles Edward, "The Young Pretender," 1720-1788 ALS to Maurepas December 29, 1747. St. Ouen, 1 l. (Box 7, Folder 55)
- Series III. Documents
  - n.d. - 1732
    - [Talmond, Anne Charles Frédérric de la Tremoille, prince de,] Group of labeled folders., 4 Items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - [Saint-Simon, Louis de Rouvray, 1675-1755] L labeled folder which held Saint-Simon's correspondance...in Maurepas file (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Folder--"Lettres au sujet de la mort de M. le M[arquis] d'Antin..." (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1 Folder--labeled "Opera." (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Artaguiette, Diron D' DS [Memoire qu'a l'honneur de presenter Monsieur de Maurepas...] [n.d., n.p.], 15 ll. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Coulomb, D [Concerns construction of 80 gun ship] [n.d., n.p.], 2 ll. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Courcy Family D [Petition to Louis XV for an increased pension] [n.d., n.p.], 1 l. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Extrait d'une lettre ycrite de Plymouth le 13 Octobre 1747, contenant la relation des combats rendus les 23 et 24 Septembre par la fregate la Renommée... [n.d., n.p.], 4 ll. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - France. Ministère de la Marine. D [Projet d'accomodement sur le 9[[ring]] article proposé par...] [n.d., n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - France. Ministère de la Marine. D [Recapitulation des demandes de retraites faites par les officiers des galères...] [n.d., n.p.], 2 ll. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - France. Ministère de la Marine. D Report, apparently concerning the children of dead officers... [n.d., n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - France. Ministère de la Marine. Une puissance brevet pour faire un fermier genéral... [n.d., n.p.], 1 l. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Macary, Antoine L to Maurepas [n.d., n.p.], 2 ll. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - [Royal Shipbuilders] D [Request, addressed to Maurepas, for an honorary title] [n.d., n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Rozier de Jonquière, AD [Family's financial situation] [n.d.], 2 ll. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Bory et Chabert AD [draft] [De quelle force il est a propos de choisir de vaisseaux pour faire le voiage de la mer du sud] [1707-1709] [n.p.], 14 ll. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Bory and Chabert AD [Remarques sur la coste du Bresil depuis Rio Genère jusques aux mines] [1707-1709] [n.p.], 10 ll. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Chabert, D Remarques sur le commerce des côtes de la Nouvelle Espagne [1707-1709] [n.p.], 3 ll. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - France. Ministère de la Marine. Material relating to the expedition of the Aimable, under Chabert, to Brazil, Chile, and Peru in 1707-1709, 3 Items. (Box 8, Folder 19)